<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clarity</title>
    <link>https://jgautierit.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Clarity</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2018–2021, Jonathan Gautier; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jgautierit.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t waste reboots in vSAN!</title>
      <link>https://jgautierit.github.io/post/2018-09-14-dont-waste-reboot-vsan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jgautierit.github.io/post/2018-09-14-dont-waste-reboot-vsan/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;This topic will focus on vSAN and more particularly to situations where a host in a vSAN cluster becomes &amp;quot;not responding&amp;quot;.
Many reasons can lead to a host becoming not responding and often a call to GSS becomes essential.
If the host is not responding, a reboot can become required as the last step and most of the time a root cause analysis will be expected.
Usually, the regular ESXi logs are not enough to diagnose the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jgautierit.github.io/iu.png&#34; alt=&#34;image alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-a-nmi&#34;&gt;Why a NMI?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NMI or Non Maskable Interrupt allows to generate the famous &amp;quot;Purple Screen Of Death&amp;quot; on the ESXi. As a consequence, a dump will be generated and will allow the analysis by VMware of the dump taken previously in order to establish a root cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;PSOD.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/PSOD.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Example2 image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jgautierit.github.io/static/images/PSOD.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Example3 image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning : A NMI should be the last step. Do not send the NMI if no troubleshooting steps was tried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-generate-a-nmi&#34;&gt;How to generate a NMI?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every vendor should have the option in their management interface like ILO or IDRAC. Please refer to their documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-grab-it-in-logs-&#34;&gt;How to grab it in logs ?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you gather the logs through ESXi via vm-support, an automatic script is going to grab the dump and put it in the vm-support tgz. As the dump can be quite heavy, please make sure that you have enough space in the directory where you will generate the support bundle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last comment but not the least, the host must have a diagnostic partition configured otherwise no dump will be collecting leading to a wasted reboot.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
